Henry F. Dobyns Papers 1732-2009 (bulk 1950-2000)
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
- Series IV: Gila River Indian Community Files, 1732-2004
  - Subseries 3: Case and Research Files, 1732-2003
    - No. 236-N Experimental Farm Disbursement Accounting, 1926 (Box 113, Folder 4)
    - No. 236-N Experimental Farm Disbursement Accounting, 1927 (Box 113, Folder 5)
    - No. 236- N Experimental Farm Disbursement Accounting, 1928 (Box 113, Folder 6)
    - No. 236-N Experimental Farm Disbursement Accounting, 1929 (Box 113, Folder 7-8)
    - No. 236-N Experimental Farm Disbursement Accounting, 1930 (Box 113, Folder 9-10)
    - No. 236-N Experimental Farm Disbursement Accounting, 1931 (Box 113, Folder 11)
    - No. 236-N Experimental Farm Disbursement Accounting, 1932 (Box 113, Folder 12-13)
    - No. 236-N Experimental Farm Disbursement Accounting, 1933 (Box 113, Folder 14)
    - No. 236-N Experimental Farm Disbursement Accounting, 1933 (Box 114, Folder 1)
    - No. 236-N Experimental Farm Disbursement Accounting, 1934 (Box 114, Folder 2-3)
    - No. 236-N Experimental Farm Disbursement Accounting, 1935 (Box 114, Folder 4-5)
    - No. 236-N Experimental Farm Disbursement Accounting, 1936 (Box 114, Folder 6-8)
    - No. 236-N Experimental Farm Disbursement Accounting, 1937 (Box 114, Folder 9-11)
    - No. 236-N Experimental Farm Disbursement Accounting, 1938 (Box 114, Folder 12-13)
    - No. 236-N Experimental Farm Disbursement Accounting, 1939 (Box 115, Folder 1-3)
    - No. 236-N Experimental Farm Disbursement Accounting, 1940 (Box 115, Folder 4-6)
    - No. 236-N Experimental Farm Disbursement Accounting, 1941 (Box 115, Folder 7-10)
    - No. 236-N Experimental Farm Disbursement Accounting, 1942 (Box 115, Folder 11)
    - No. 236-N Experimental Farm Disbursement Accounting, 1943 (Box 115, Folder 12)
    - No. 236-N Experimental Farm Disbursement Accounting, 1944 (Box 115, Folder 13-15)
    - No. 236-N Experimental Farm Disbursement Accounting, 1945 (Box 116, Folder 1)
    - No. 236-N Experimental Farm Disbursement Accounting, 1946 (Box 116, Folder 2-3)
    - No. 236-N Experimental Farm Disbursement Accounting, 1947 (Box 116, Folder 4)
    - No. 236-N Experimental Farm Receipt Accounting, 1910-1919 (Box 116, Folder 5-6)
    - No. 236-N Experimental Farm Receipt Accounting, 1919-1929 (Box 116, Folder 7-9)
    - No. 236-N Experimental Farm Receipt Accounting, 1930-1937 (Box 116, Folder 10-11)
    - No. 236-N Experimental Farm Receipt Accounting, 1938-1947 (Box 116, Folder 12-14)
    - No. 236-N Pre-1883 Accounting for the Act of Feb. 28, 1859 Disbursement (Box 116, Folder 15)
    - No. 236- Pleadings, 1972-1974 (Box 116, Folder 16)
    - No. 236- Pleadings, 1977-1982 (Box 117, Folder 1)
    - No. 236- Pleadings, 1983 (Box 117, Folder 2-5)
    - No. 236- Pleadings, 1984 (Box 117, Folder 6)
    - No. 236- Pleadings, 1985 (Box 117, Folder 7-8)
    - No. 236- Pleadings, 1986-1991 (Box 117, Folder 9)
    - No. 236- Pleadings, 1997-1998 (Box 117, Folder 10)
    - No. 236- Pleadings, undated (Box 117, Folder 11)
    - No. 236- Trial transcripts November 8, 1983 (Box 117, Folder 12-13)
    - No. 236- Trial transcripts November 15, 1983 (Box 117, Folder 14)
    - No. 236- Trial transcripts, 1991 (Box 118, Folder 1)
    - No. 291- Pleadings, 1981 (Box 118, Folder 2)
    - No. 6417- Court Issued documents, 1991-1993 (Box 118, Folder 3)
    - No. 6417- Pleadings, 1992-1993 (Box 118, Folder 4-6)
    - Notes, 1978-1985 (Box 118, Folder 7)
    - Notes, 1986-1998 (Box 118, Folder 8)
    - Notes, undated (Box 118, Folder 9-11)
    - Office of the Gila River Water Commissioner memos, 1991-1995 (Box 118, Folder 12)
    - Orders of Appointment by Gila Water Commissioner, 1990 (Box 118, Folder 13-14)
    - Phase One Reconnaissance Water Budget report, 1989 (Box 118, Folder 15)
    - Phoenix Indian School, 1987 (Box 118, Folder 16)
    - Pima Experimental Farm, 1908-1911 (Box 118, Folder 17)
    - Pima-Maricopa Demographic Trend, 1846-1946 documents, undated (Box 118, Folder 18)
    - Plaintiffs’ reply to defendant’s brief on Issue F, undated (Box 119, Folder 1)
    - Pomerene Water Users’ Association reports, 1994 (Box 119, Folder 2)
    - Proceedings of First Conference of Engineers of the Reclamation Service, 1904 (Box 119, Folder 3)
    - Qualifications of Henry F. Dobyns as expert on the history of human cultural adjustment to arid environments, 1986 (Box 119, Folder 4)
    - Rea, Amadeo- Phreatophytes River Pima and Maricopa Mesquite Usage Destruction of Pima-Maricopa Prosperity, 1999 (Box 119, Folder 5)
    - Rea, Amadeo- Phreatophytes River Pima and Maricopa Mesquite Usage Destruction of Pima-Maricopa Prosperity, 2000 (Box 119, Folder 6)
    - Receipts and Disbursements for the Gila River Reservation Experimental Farm 1908 through 1947, 1984 (Box 119, Folder 7-8)
    - Report of the Commissioner of Indian Affairs, 1872-1900 (Box 119, Folder 9)
    - Report of the Commissioner of Indian Affairs, 1903-1911 (Box 119, Folder 10)
    - Report of Herbert E. Skibitzke P.E. regarding Globe Equity 59, 1990 (Box 119, Folder 11)
    - Report on Economic Conditions existing on the San Carlos Irrigation and the Gila River Indian Reservation, Arizona, 1944 (Box 119, Folder 12-13)
    - Report on Water Supply of the Lower Colorado River Basin Project Planning Report, 1952 (Box 119, Folder 14-16)
    - Research documents, 1775-1889 (Box 119, Folder 17)
    - Research documents, 1775-1889 (Box 120, Folder 1)
    - Research documents, 1900-1929 (Box 120, Folder 2-6)
    - Research documents, 1930-1949 (Box 120, Folder 7-13)
    - Research documents, 1930-1949 (Box 121, Folder 1-2)
    - Research documents, 1950-1995 (Box 121, Folder 3-10)
    - Research documents- Gila River Commissioner, 1936-1962 (Box 121, Folder 11-14)
    - Research documents- Gila River Commissioner, 1936-1962 (Box 122, Folder 1-2)
    - Resolution- Ezell, undated (Box 122, Folder 3)
    - Safadi, Assad- Crop Water Requirements for the Pomerene Water Users Association (PWUA) San Pedro River Watershed Arizona, 1994 (Box 122, Folder 4)
    - San Carlos Indian Irrigation Project research notes, 1991-1995 (Box 122, Folder 5)
    - San Carlos Irrigation Project- Monthly Project report, 1985 (Box 122, Folder 6)
    - San Carlos Irrigation Project- Monthly Water Distribution Report, 1992-1995 (Box 122, Folder 7)
    - San Carlos Water, 1912-1996 (Box 122, Folder 8-9)
    - San Pedro Hydrographic Survey Report memos, 1991, 1994 (Box 122, Folder 10)
    - San Pedro meetings, 1992-1996 (Box 122, Folder 11)
    - San Pedro River Adjudication expert witness report- Gallacher, Daniel, 1994 (Box 122, Folder 12)
    - San Pedro River Case Tenneco Motion of Summary Judgment- Affidavit, 1986 (Box 122, Folder 13-14)
    - San Pedro River Watershed orientation sessions, 1993 (Box 122, Folder 15)
    - Sayles, E.B.- The Hohokam Culture as related to other Southwestern Cultures, 1962 (Box 122, Folder 16)
    - Schumm, S.A.- River Geomorphology and the San Pedro River, undated (Box 122, Folder 17)
    - Settlement Act, 1991 (Box 122, Folder 18)
    - Smith, G.E.P- Oil Engines for Pump Irrigation and the Cost of Pumping, 1915 (Box 122, Folder 19)
    - South Pass Resources- Adjudication of the Gila River System: Subflow and Percolating Ground-water Identification Criteria, 1993 (Box 122, Folder 20)
    - Spicer, Edward- Cycles of Conquest, 1967 (Box 122, Folder 21)
    - SRP documents, 1886-1966 (Box 122, Folder 22)
    - SRP documents, 1886-1966 (Box 123, Folder 1)
    - Statues at large of the US, 1860-1880 (Box 123, Folder 2)
    - Stephens, John- Conserving the Rights of Pima Indians, 1912 (Box 123, Folder 3)
    - Stetson Engineers- The Delineation of Subflow in the San Pedro River Basin, Arizona, 1993 (Box 123, Folder 4)
    - Stetson Engineers- The Interrelationships of Basin Ground water and Surface and Subsurface flow of the San Pedro River Basin, Arizona, 1987 (Box 123, Folder 5)
    - Stetson Engineers- On-Farm Engineering, Cost Estimation and Water Requirements for the Gila River Indian Reservation, 2002 (Box 123, Folder 6)
    - Stetson Engineers- Preliminary Investigation of Cosper’s Crossing Condition, 1994 (Box 123, Folder 7-8)
    - Stetson Engineers- Preliminary Review of Crops of Value Gila River Basin, 1994 (Box 123, Folder 9)
    - Stetson Engineers- Preliminary Review of the Suitability of the Quality of Gila River Water to Irrigate Lands of the San Carlos Apache Reservation, Arizona, 1994 (Box 123, Folder 10)
    - Stetson Engineers- Preliminary Review of Transit and Seepage Losses, 1994 (Box 123, Folder 11)
    - Stetson Engineers- Review of the Arizona Department of Water Resources Hydrographic Survey Report for the Gila River Indian Reservation, 1997 (Box 123, Folder 12)
    - Stetson Engineers- Review of the Modified Preliminary Hydrographic Survey Report for the San Pedro River Watershed, 1990 (Box 123, Folder 13)
    - Stetson Engineers- Review of the Technical Aspects of the Globe Equity No. 59 Case, Gila Decree Counts one through four, 1990 (Box 123, Folder 14)
    - Thomas, Robert- Papago Land Use, 1963 (Box 123, Folder 15)
    - Treaty of Guadalupe Hidalgo, 1848 (Box 123, Folder 16)
    - Truesdell, John correspondence, 1918-1919 (Box 123, Folder 17)
    - Truesdell, John documents, 1996 (Box 123, Folder 18)
    - USGS Annual Report, 1901 (Box 123, Folder 19)
    - USGS maps, 1960, 1985 (Box 123, Folder 20)
    - US National Archives sources, undated (Box 123, Folder 21)
    - University of Arizona sources, undated (Box 123, Folder 22)
    - Van Willigen, John- Development of Papago Communities: Strategies Results and Problems, 1973 (Box 123, Folder 23)
    - Water Commissioner’s Reports, 1938 (Box 123, Folder 24)
    - Water in the 20th Century West: Documenting the Arizona Experience, 1990 (Box 123, Folder 25)
    - Water rights, undated (Box 123, Folder 26)
    - Water rights memo, 1987 (Box 123, Folder 27)
    - Water rights registration, 1990 (Box 123, Folder 28)
    - Water users meeting- San Carlos Indian Works, 1994 (Box 124, Folder 1)
    - Watershed file report numbers, 1992 (Box 124, Folder 2)
    - WC-1- Pleadings, 1984 (Box 124, Folder 3)
    - WC-90- Court Issued documents, 1992-2001 (Box 124, Folder 4)
    - WC-90- Pleadings, 1992 (Box 124, Folder 5-9)
    - WC-90- Pleadings, 1994 (Box 124, Folder 10-11)
    - WC-90- Pleadings, 1995 (Box 124, Folder 12-13)
    - Well reports- Franklin, 1990 (Box 124, Folder 14)
    - Well reports- Gila Valley, 1990 (Box 124, Folder 15)
    - Wellendorf, William- A Proposal to Define Approachable Subflow for the Gila River System and Source Based on Geomorphic and Hydrogeologic Criteria, 1993 (Box 124, Folder 16)
    - Wellendorf, William- A Proposal to Define the Nature of the “Dry up” at Cosper’s Crossing- Duncan- Virden Basin, Arizona, 1994 (Box 124, Folder 17)
    - Winkleman articles, 1956 (Box 124, Folder 18)
    - Winters v US, 1907 (Box 124, Folder 19)
    - Woods, Clyde- Native American Cultural Resources (Ethnology), 1981 (Box 124, Folder 20)
    - Workshop on tribal water resources, 1985 (Box 124, Folder 21)
    - W1- Pleadings, 1981-1985 (Box 124, Folder 22)
    - W1- Pleadings, 1981-1985 (Box 125, Folder 1)
    - W1- San Pedro River System, 1981 (Box 125, Folder 2-3)
    - W1-11- Court Issued documents, 1991-1995 (Box 125, Folder 4)
    - W1-11- Objection forms, 1992 (Box 125, Folder 5-7)
    - W1-11- Pleadings, 1991-1993 (Box 125, Folder 8-10)
    - W1-11- Pleadings, 1994 (Box 125, Folder 11)
    - W1-11- Pleadings, 1995 (Box 125, Folder 12)
    - W1-11- Trial transcripts March 22, 1994 (Box 125, Folder 13-14)
    - W1-11- Trial transcripts March 23, 1994 (Box 125, Folder 15)
    - W1-11- Trial transcripts March 24, 1994 (Box 126, Folder 1)
    - W1-11- Trial transcripts March 25, 1994 (Box 126, Folder 2)
    - W1-11- Trial transcripts March 29, 1994 (Box 126, Folder 3)
    - W1-11- Trial transcripts March 30, 1994 (Box 126, Folder 4)
    - W1-11- Trial transcripts March 31, 1994 (Box 126, Folder 5)
    - W1-100- Pleadings, 1996 (Box 126, Folder 6)
    - W1-200- Pleadings, 1991 (Box 126, Folder 7)
    - W1-201- Pleadings, 1993 (Box 126, Folder 8)
    - W1-203- Court Issued documents, 2000 (Box 126, Folder 9)
    - W1-203- Pleadings, 1998 (Box 126, Folder 10)
    - W1-203- Pleadings, 1999 (Box 126, Folder 11-15)
    - W1-203- Pleadings, 1999 (Box 127, Folder 1-4)
    - W1-203- Pleadings, 2000 (Box 127, Folder 5-9)
    - W1-206- Pleadings, 2001 (Box 127, Folder 10-11)
    - W1, W2, W3, W4- Court Issued documents, 1993-1997 (Box 127, Folder 12)
    - W1, W1, W3, W4- De Minimus Water Users, 1993-1994 (Box 127, Folder 13-14)
    - W1, W2, W3, W4- Pleadings, 1986 (Box 128, Folder 1-2)
    - W1, W2, W3, W4- Pleadings, 1989-1993 (Box 128, Folder 3-4)
    - W1, W2, W3, W4- Pleadings, 1994 (Box 128, Folder 5)
    - W1, W2, W3, W4- Pleadings, 1995-1999 (Box 128, Folder 6)
    - Young, Don- An Alienation Delineation of Appropriable Subflow and Groundwater in the State of Arizona, 1993 (Box 128, Folder 7)
    - Young, Don- An Overview of Groundwater/Surface Water Interrelationships, 1987 (Box 128, Folder 8)
  - Subseries 4: Miscellaneous, 1974-2004
    This subseries contains contracts, billing statements to Cox & Cox for expert assistance as well as material related to the creation of the Indian Studies Institute. Boxes 128-129.
    - Awards, 1993 (Box 128, Folder 9)
    - Contact lists, 1984 (Box 128, Folder 10)
    - Contracts, 1974-2004 (Box 128, Folder 11)
    - Expert assistance billing, 1983-1988 (Box 128, Folder 12)
    - Expert assistance billing, 1989 (Box 128, Folder 13)
    - Expert assistance billing, 1990 (Box 128, Folder 14-15)
    - Expert assistance billing, 1991 (Box 128, Folder 16)
    - Expert assistance billing, 1992 (Box 128, Folder 17)
    - Expert assistance billing, 1993-1995 (Box 128, Folder 18)
    - Expert assistance billing, 1996-1999 (Box 129, Folder 1)
    - Indian Studies Institute, 1986 (Box 129, Folder 2)
    - Suggested expert assistance budget, 1986, 1994 (Box 129, Folder 3)
- Series V: Cornell Peru Project Files, 1943-1980
  This series contains material related to Dobyns work with Cornell University on the Cornell Peru Project. Dr. Dobyns worked on several different projects within the Cornell Peru Project including Andean Indian Community Research and Development, Comparative Studies for Cultural Change and Peace Corps volunteer training and evaluation. This includes work in several South American countries and Thailand. Additional material related to the Cornell Peru Project can be located in the Cornell University Library. This Series is divided into 4 subseries. This series is arranged alphabetically. Most of the material is in Spanish.
  - Subseries 1: Writings, 1946-1976
    This subseries contains the manuscripts, articles and conference papers produced by the Cornell Peru Project team including Dr. Dobyns, staff members and students pertaining to research and data collection primarily in Peru. Boxes 129-135.
    - Actitud y Conducta Hacia una Innovacion Tecnológica, undated (Box 129, Folder 4)
    - Agricultural and related Innovation in Vicos, 1969 (Box 129, Folder 5)
    - Agricultural Production on Hacienda Vicos, undated (Box 129, Folder 6)
    - American Association for the Advancement of Science- The Transformation of Suppressed Peasant Societies, 1964 (Box 129, Folder 7)
    - American Society for Ethnohistory- Cornell Peru Project, 1960-1966 (Box 129, Folder 8-9)
    - An Analysis of One Week’s reporting of an Incident of Interracial Violence in the Peruvian Andes by the Lima Daily Press, 1960 (Box 129, Folder 10)
    - An Analysis of Vicos Schoolboy Perception of their Kinship System, 1961 (Box 129, Folder 11)
    - The Analysis of Western Civilization by Anthropological Methods, 1960 (Box 129, Folder 12)
    - Antropologia y Medicina, 1957 (Box 129, Folder 13)
    - Aquia and Caranavi: Two Cases of Internal Migration in the Andes, undated (Box 129, Folder 14)
    - Aspects of Mestizo-White Relations in Capilla Loma, 1960 (Box 129, Folder 15)
    - Autonomy and Respect, 1965 (Box 129, Folder 16)
    - The Avalanche at Ranrahirca, 1962 (Box 129, Folder 17)
    - Aymara Biculturalism and Sociopsychological Adjustment in Bolivia, undated (Box 129, Folder 18)
    - Basic Problems of Development in the Callejon de Huaylas, 1961 (Box 129, Folder 19)
    - Bibliografia del Proyecto Peru Cornell 1951- Junio 1965, 1966 (Box 129, Folder 20)
    - Bibliography of the Cornell Thailand Project, 1947-1962 (Box 129, Folder 21)
    - Bolivia Comparisons, undated (Box 129, Folder 22)
    - Case Studies of Subsistence and Transition: Vicos, Peru, 1965 (Box 129, Folder 23)
    - Las Castas de Vicos, Peru, undated (Box 129, Folder 24)
    - The Castas: Unilineal Kin Groups in Vicos, Peru, 1966 (Box 129, Folder 25)
    - Central Andean Government Policies and Cultural Pluralism, undated (Box 129, Folder 26)
    - Ceremonial Kinship in a Peruvian Town, 1964 (Box 129, Folder 27)
    - Change Without Design in the Central Andes, 1966 (Box 129, Folder 28)
    - Chicha in the Central Andean Countries, 1965 (Box 130, Folder 1)
    - Chicherias in Three Peruvian Provincial Capitals, 1966 (Box 130, Folder 2)
    - Child Training in Vicos, Peru, 1951 (Box 130, Folder 3)
    - Civic Violence in Peru during 1960, 1961 (Box 130, Folder 4)
    - Class and the Schools in Huaylas, Peru, 1960 (Box 130, Folder 5)
    - Coca Chewing: A Social versus a Nutritional Interpretation, 1960 (Box 130, Folder 6)
    - Coming Down the Mountain: The Social World of Mayobamba- Spanish translation, 1974 (Box 130, Folder 7-9)
    - Comments on Richard N. Adams’ Rural Labor in Latin America, 1963 (Box 130, Folder 10)
    - Commercial Activity in a Peruvian Community, 1961 (Box 130, Folder 11)
    - Community Organization and Culture Change in Huaylas, Peru, 1961 (Box 130, Folder 12)
    - ¿Como Entrar en la Comunidad?, undated (Box 130, Folder 13)
    - A Comparison of Drinking Patterns in Three Hispanic Cities, 1965 (Box 130, Folder 14)
    - Comunidades Camesinas del Peru, 1970 (Box 130, Folder 15)
    - Concepts of Disease in a Peruvian Indian Community, 1962 (Box 130, Folder 16)
    - Considerations for the Strategy and Tactics of Planned Change in the Peruvian Andes, 1966 (Box 130, Folder 17)
    - A Contagious Experiment: The Vicos Idea has Spread throughout Peru, 1962 (Box 130, Folder 18)
    - Cooperacion Popular and Sayan Peru, 1965 (Box 130, Folder 19)
    - Cornell Latin American Year, 1966 (Box 130, Folder 20)
    - The Cornell Peru Project, 1967, 1977 (Box 130, Folder 21)
    - The Cornell Peru Project Bibliography and Personnel, 1964 (Box 130, Folder 22)
    - Cornell Peru Project Contribution to Applied Anthropology, 1961 (Box 130, Folder 23)
    - The Cornell Peru Project Vicos Experiment and the Future of Peru: A Position paper for Allan R. Holmberg, 1962 (Box 130, Folder 24)
    - The Cornell Peru Project Vicos Experiment in Guided Cultural Change and Manorial System Reform: A Photographic Report, 1968 (Box 130, Folder 25)
    - Credit Functions in Cultural Change: The Vicos Case, 1961 (Box 130, Folder 26)
    - Culture, Migration and Fertility in Peru, undated (Box 130, Folder 27)
    - The Dance in Viru, 1965 (Box 130, Folder 28)
    - Developmental Change in Well being in Mountain Mayobamba, 1967 (Box 130, Folder 29)
    - A Discovery, undated (Box 130, Folder 30)
    - Drinking Patterns in Highland Ecuador, 1965 (Box 130, Folder 31)
    - Drinking Patterns in Latin America: A Review, 1966 (Box 130, Folder 32)
    - Dynamic Functionalism, 1969 (Box 130, Folder 33)
    - An Economic Assessment of Pioneer Settlements in the Bolivian Tropics, 1965 (Box 131, Folder 1)
    - Economic Importance and its Relation to Attitudes in a Group of Viru Women, 1965 (Box 131, Folder 2)
    - Ecuadorian Costumes and Textiles, undated (Box 131, Folder 3)
    - Educacion formal en un Comunidad Rural Indigena: Vicos, undated (Box 131, Folder 4)
    - An Empirical Deprivation of the Social Interaction System of Virú, 1965 (Box 131, Folder 5)
    - An Essay on Andean Policemen, undated (Box 131, Folder 6)
    - Estructuras de Mercados Peruanos, 1970 (Box 131, Folder 7)
    - Un Estudio de la Prensa Diaria del Peru, undated (Box 131, Folder 8)
    - Ethnic Group Land Rights in the Modern State: Three Cases Studies, 1961-1962 (Box 131, Folder 9)
    - Experimental Participant Intervention in Puerto Rico, 1964 (Box 131, Folder 10)
    - The Eye of an Artist, 1964 (Box 131, Folder 11)
    - Factors in Strategic Intervention in Community Life, 1966 (Box 131, Folder 12)
    - Farm- Market Roads in National Development in the Central Andes, undated (Box 131, Folder 13)
    - First Cousin Marriages in a Puerto Rican Pentecostal Community, 1966 (Box 131, Folder 14)
    - From Buckets into Pipes: Participant Intervention in Providing Piped Domestic Water to a Puerto Rican Hamlet, 1965 (Box 131, Folder 15)
    - Historical Perspectives on Alcoholic Beverages Consumption in Mestizo America, 1970 (Box 131, Folder 16)
    - The History of the Founding of a Community in the Andes and the Development of its arts and crafts, 1965 (Box 131, Folder 17)
    - Holy Places and their Effects on Conduct in Vicos, Ancash, Peru, 1965 (Box 131, Folder 18)
    - Hospital de Belen in Huaraz, Peru, 1965 (Box 131, Folder 19)
    - Human Freedom and Geographic Mobility, 1964-1965 (Box 131, Folder 20)
    - Immigración y Mestizaje en el Peru durante el Siglo XIX, 1965 (Box 131, Folder 21)
    - Indigenismo Científico, 1961 (Box 131, Folder 22)
    - Indigenous Community Response to Mass Medium Stimulus, undated (Box 131, Folder 23)
    - Iniciativa Comunal entre Comunidades Indigenas Peruanas, 1963 (Box 131, Folder 24)
    - The Introduction of Democratic Municipal Government in a Peruvian Coastal Community, 1964 (Box 131, Folder 25)
    - José León: The Story of a Peruvian Indian, 1968 (Box 131, Folder 26)
    - La Junta de Obras Publicas de Ancash, 1964 (Box 131, Folder 27)
    - The Kami Mine, 1969 (Box 131, Folder 28-29)
    - Land Reform Showdown, 1960 (Box 131, Folder 30)
    - Land Tenure and Development in Latin America, 1964 (Box 131, Folder 31)
    - Livestock Immunization in Vicos, Peru, undated (Box 131, Folder 32)
    - Manual for AID, undated (Box 132, Folder 1)
    - Marcará- Census y Analysis, 1961 (Box 132, Folder 2)
    - Methodological Limits to Cultural Relativism, 1963 (Box 132, Folder 3)
    - Methods for the Analysis of Cultural Change, 1961 (Box 132, Folder 4)
    - Methods for Analyzing Change, 1946-1963 (Box 132, Folder 5)
    - Mexico’s Federal Corn Warehouses in Highland Chiapas, 1962 (Box 132, Folder 6)
    - Migración e Integración en el Perú, 1963 (Box 132, Folder 7)
    - La Migracion, regionalismo y el Desarrollo Local, undated (Box 132, Folder 8)
    - Minor Crop Communities: La Cuesta and Montería, Coamo, 1965 (Box 132, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous, 1961-1962, undated (Box 132, Folder 10)
    - Modernization of Indigenous Communities in the Andes, 1962 (Box 132, Folder 11)
    - Movement with Progress: A Study of Union Activity in Peru, 1960 (Box 132, Folder 12)
    - Opinion Publica y Comunicacion en la Provincia de Tarma, 1962 (Box 132, Folder 13)
    - An Outline of Andean Epidemic History to 1720, 1962 (Box 132, Folder 14)
    - Outlines, 1968-1976, undated (Box 132, Folder 15)
    - El Padron de Comunidades Indigenas, 1961 (Box 132, Folder 16)
    - Participant Intervention in Providing Domestic Water, 1964 (Box 132, Folder 17)
    - Peasant Society in Transition, 1961 (Box 132, Folder 18)
    - Peasants, Politics and Drinking Patterns, undated (Box 132, Folder 19)
    - Peasants, Power and Applied Social Change, 1970-1971 (Box 132, Folder 20-22)
    - Peruvian Newspaper Characteristics, 1961 (Box 132, Folder 23)
    - A Peruvian Trucking Industry, 1964-1965 (Box 132, Folder 24)